Hui Ye

Research Focus

My research interests lie in the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) and Computer Graphics (CG). Specifically, my main research focus is on exploring novel mobile AR prototyping tools and techniques for 3D contents and interactions.

Education

City University of Hong Kong (CityU)

Sep 2017-Aug 2022

Ph.D. in Creative Media Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

Thesis: 3D Content and Interaction Prototyping with Mobile Augmented Reality

• University of Science and Technology of China (USTC)

Sep 2012-June 2016

B.A. in Communication

Minor in Computer Science and Technology

Experience

• RGC Postdoctoral Fellow, City University of Hong Kong

Sep 2022-Current

Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

• Research Assistant, City University of Hong Kong

Sep 2021-Aug 2022

Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

• Visiting Ph.D. student, Tsinghua University

Dec 2019-Apr 2020

Institute of HCI and Media Integration

Advisors: Dr. Chun Yu and Prof. Hongbo Fu

City University of Hong Kong

Sep-Dec 2014

Exchange student

Publications

- **Hui Ye**, Jiaye Leng, Chufeng Xiao, Lili Wang and Hongbo Fu. 2023. ProObjAR: Prototyping Spatially-aware Interactions of Smart Objects with AR-HMD. In *Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI 2023).
- **Hui Ye** and Hongbo Fu. 2022. ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-world IoT Enhanced Spaces. In *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI 2022).
- **Hui Ye**, Kin Chung Kwan, and Hongbo Fu. 2021. 3D Curve Creation on and around Physical Objects with Mobile AR. In *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG)*.
- **Hui Ye**, Kin Chung Kwan (joint first author), Wanchao Su, and Hongbo Fu. 2020. ARAnimator: In-situ Character Animation in Mobile AR with User-defined Motion Gestures. In *ACM Transactions on Graphics (Special Issue of ACM SIGGRAPH* 2020).
- Wanchao Su, Hui Ye, Shuyu Chen, Lin Gao, and Hongbo Fu. 2022. DrawingInStyles: Portrait Image Generation and Editing with Spatially Conditioned StyleGAN. In *IEEE Transactions on Visualization* and Computer Graphics (TVCG).
- Xuanyu Wang, Hui Ye, Christian Sandor, Weizhan Zhang, and Hongbo Fu. 2022. Predict-and-Drive: Avatar Motion Adaption in Room-Scale Augmented Reality Telepresence with Heterogeneous Spaces.

In IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG): Special Issue for IEEE ISMAR 2022.

- Yanxiang Zhang and **Hui Ye**. 2016. Time-Based Nonlinear Interactive Player. In *International Conference on Augmented Reality, Virtual Reality and Computer Graphics*. Springer, Cham.
- Yanxiang Zhang, Yun Zhu, **Hui Ye**. 2015. The Design of an Augmented Reality Based Rigid Body Motion Experiment System. In *Applied Mechanics and Materials*. Trans Tech Publications Ltd.

Selected Honors & Awards

RGC Postdoctoral Fellowship	2022
Outstanding Academic Performance Award of CityU	2021
Shidi CAD&CG Excellent Student Award	2021
Research Tuition Scholarship of CityU	2020
o Guo Moruo Scholarship (Top 2%, Highest Honor for USTC Undergraduates)	2016
 Merit Graduate of Anhui Province & USTC (Top 3%) 	2016
 Certificate of Honorary Rank of USTC (Top 5%) 	2016
 Outstanding Thesis of USTC 	2016
Sun Bin Leadership Scholarship of USTC	2014
 Aegon-Industrial Responsibility Scholarship of USTC 	2014
 Outstanding Instructor in "Science and Technology Week" of USTC 	2013-15
o Gold Award of Excellent Student Scholarship of USTC (Top 5%)	2013
 Outstanding Young Volunteer of USTC 	2013
Talks	
 The Road from Communication to Computer Graphics Invited Presenter, Student Colloquium, CAD&CG 2022+2023 	Aug 2022
 ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-worldIoT Enhanced Spaces Conference Paper Presenter, CHI 2022 	May 2022
 Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions Invited Speaker, EAA Youth Academic Forum, Tianjin Fine Arts Institute 	Apr 2022
 Exploring Novel Mobile AR Prototyping Techniques and Tools for 3D Contents and Interactions SIGGRAPH Thesis Fast Forward 	Dec 2021
 ARAnimator: In-situ Character Animation in Mobile AR with User-defined Motion Gestures 	
Invited Speaker, Graphics And Mixed Environment Symposium (GAMES)	Sep 2021
Invited Speaker, SCM ACIM Colloquium, CityU	Oct 2020
Conference Paper Presenter, SIGGRAPH 2020	Aug 2020
 3D Curve Creation on and around Physical Objects with Mobile AR Invited Speaker, IEEE VR 2021 	Mar 2021
 In-situ 3D Content Creation in Mobile AR Invited Speaker, Affiliated Forum on Human, Technology and Future of IWHEC 2021 	Mar 2021

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant, CityU SM1103A Introduction to Media Computing

2018 & 19 Fall

Professional Service

- Paper Review: SIGGRAPH Asia 2023 & 2022, CHI 2023 & 2022 & 2020, PG 2023 & 2020, UIST 2022, MobileHCI 2022, IEEE VR 2021, IEEE AIVR 2021, TVCG, Visual Computer
- Program Committees: CSCW 2024 (July) & 2023 (January), CHI 2023 Late-Breaking Work, Jury Member of CHI 2022 Student Research Competition
- Student Helper: PG 2018

Skills

o Programming Language: C#, Swift, Python, HTML

Graphics interface: OpenCV, QT

o Application Tools: iOS App, ARKit, HoloLens, Mixed Reality Toolkit

o Hardware: HoloLens, Arduino, Motion Capture

Last updated on July 6, 2023